
--- 2407.11267v1.md ---


Enhancing Multi-Step Brent Oil Price Forecasting with
Ensemble Multi-Scenario Bi-GRU Networks
## Mohammed Alruqimi
a
## , Luca Di Persio
a
a
University of Verona, Verona, Italy
## Abstract
Despite  numerous  research  efforts  in  applying  deep  learning  to  time  series
forecasting, achieving high accuracy in multi-step predictions for volatile time
series like crude oil prices remains a significant challenge.  Moreover,  most
existing approaches primarily focus on one-step forecasting, and the perfor-
mance often varies depending on the dataset and specific case study.  In this
paper, we introduce an ensemble model to capture Brent oil price volatility
and  enhance  the  multi-step  prediction.   Our  methodology  employs  a  two-
pronged approach.  First, we assess popular deep-learning models and the im-
pact of various external factors on forecasting accuracy.  Then, we introduce
an ensemble multi-step forecasting model for Brent oil prices.  Our approach
generates accurate forecasts by employing ensemble techniques across mul-
tiple forecasting scenarios using three BI-GRU networks.  Extensive experi-
ments were conducted on a dataset encompassing the COVID-19 pandemic
period,  which  had  a  significant  impact  on  energy  markets.   The  proposed
modelΓÇÖs performance was evaluated using the standard evaluation metrics of
## Γêù
corresponding author
Email addresses:mohammed.alruqimi@univr.it(Mohammed Alruqimi),
luca.dipersio@univr.it(Luca Di Persio)


--- 3789297.3789333.md ---


## Forecasting Crude Oil Prices Using Deep Learning Models
## Longxuan Li
Beijing Institute of Technology
## Zhuhai, China
## O13458658971@gmail.com
## Xingyu Cheng
Beijing Institute of Technology
## Zhuhai, China
maojiuaston@gmail.com
## Yiyang Zhang
Beijing Institute of Technology
## Zhuhai, China
## 2736453970@qq.com
## Dan Zhu
## Γêù
Faculty of Social Science
Beijing Institute of Technology
## Zhuhai, China
## 6220218349@bitzh.edu.cn
## Abstract
Crude oil prices represent one of the most critical macroeconomic
variables in the global economy, exerting profound impacts on
energy security, economic growth, and financial market stability.
However, their sharp fluctuations, nonlinear dynamics, volatility
clustering, and regime shifts undermine the predictive power of
traditional linear models. This study aims to enhance crude oil
price forecasting performance through deep learning techniques by
constructing and comparing several hybrid neural network mod-


--- preprintofpaper.md ---


Directional Forecasting of WTI and Brent Crude Oil
Prices: A Machine Learning Approach with
Technical Indicators at Daily, Weekly, and Monthly
## Frequencies
## Badr Alnssyan
## Qassim University
## Muhammad Ali
## Abdul Wali Khan University Mardan
## Muhammad Ahmad
## Abdul Wali Khan University Mardan
## Research Article
Keywords: Statistical models, ARIMA, Machine learning, WTI, Brent oil
## Posted Date: December 16th, 2025
DOI: https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-8253110/v1
License: ∩ë₧ ∩ôº This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.
## Read Full License
Additional Declarations: No competing interests reported.

Directional Forecasting of WTI and Brent Crude
Oil Prices: A Machine Learning Approach with
Technical Indicators at Daily, Weekly, and
## Monthly Frequencies
## Badr Alnssyan
## 1
## ,  Muhammad Ali
## 2*
## ,  Muhammad Ahmad
## 2

